REYNA G. ORTIZ

6928 10th Street, Rio Linda CA · 916-202-6943

Reyna.ortiz84@gmail.com · LinkedIn Profile: linkedin.com/in/reyna-ortiz-b8725554

Experienced professional with the ability to analyze complex data, identify trends, and make recommendations. Effective communicator of complex information in an empathetic and helpful manner. Strong organizational and critical thinking skills that allow for providing effective solutions to meet organizational goals and objectives.

EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2018 – PRESENT PAYROLL ANALYST, ORACLE

Successfully coordinates the payroll process for various Latin American countries, collects and records information in various tracking applications. Delivers complex information to a multilingual customer base. Creates trainings and facilitates training sessions for employees. Analyzes complex data and provides recommendations on observed trends.

JUNE 2018 - OCTOBER 2018

ACCOUNTING ASSISTANT, STRATEGIES TO EMPOWER PEOPLE

Experience working in a public health program. Supported the deaf/blind community from a payroll and small-business accounting perspective. Learned valuable skills in communicating with individuals with varying levels of physical disabilities. Received Pro-ACT training to help communicate and support individuals experiencing a crisis. The program also required access to sensitive medical history and personal information, which I handled with empathy, discretion, and professionalism.

JULY 2004 - JANUARY 2017

ATTENDANCE COORDINATOR JUN-2009 TO JAN-2017, VERIZON WIRELESS

Utilized critical thinking skills to understand and apply California Labor Laws when auditing attendance and leave benefits. Handled sensitive information (i.e. corrective actions, leave of absence information, and worker's comp) in a professional manner. Worked with various computer software's and a workflow manager to ensure consistency and standardization of processes.

RESOURCE COORDINATOR DEC-2006 TO JUN-2009, VERIZON WIRELESS

Utilized various call-monitoring software's with the goal of ensuring an excellent customer experience. Communicated with various levels of leadership regarding live call center statistics. Monitored bilingual queues to identify quality improvement opportunities and communicated recommendations to employees. Provided ad hoc reporting to management regarding metrics, as well as anticipated and reported on trending items to ensure we had an accurate headcount for to answer our customers within the acceptable service level. Facilitated training sessions to deliver complex information so employees can understand tracking metrics.

BILINGUAL COORDINATOR JUL-2004 TO DEC-2006, VERIZON WIRELESS

Utilized excellent interpersonal skills to solve customer concerns with empathy and professionalism. Consistently met and exceeded metrics for the bilingual department. Participated in a leadership mentorship program. Received Employee of the Month Award for my focus on the customer experience.

JUNE 2003 - JUNE 2004

BILINGUAL MEDI-CAL ENROLLMENT COORDINATOR, MAXIMUS

Provided accurate and efficient customer service support to Medi-Cal recipients in the enrollment of a health care option. Utilized a CRM to document information provided as well as to audit for data integrity.

EDUCATION

JULY 2010

BACHELOR OF SIENCE BUSINESS MANAGEMENT, UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX

Received a 3.74 GPA as well as learned how to communicate effectively and empathetically. Learned how to read financial reports and create an action plan to implement changes needed to accomplish organizational goals. Additionally, learned how to work with professionals of a culturally diverse background with courses focused on the psychology of decision-making.

AUGUST 2004

ASSOCIATES IN BUSINESS SOFTWARE APPLICATIONS, HEALD COLLEGE

Received a 3.89 GPA as well as student of the quarter award. Learned how to troubleshoot computer software and hardware. Began learning of Myers-Briggs Indicators to help with understanding how different people process information and make decisions.

SKILLS

- Excellent time management skills
- Reliable team player
- Efficiency focused
- Proficiency in managing uncertainty
- Trilingual (English/Spanish/beginner's Portuguese)
- Problem-solver and concise communicator
- Ability to handle sensitive information ethically

ACTIVITIES

Supports the vulnerable community in our neighborhood by organizing food deliveries and picking up trash in our greenspaces. Enjoys learning about new cultures and languages, most recently I have enjoyed learning about Brazilian culture and the similarities with Portuguese and Spanish languages.